# **ALEX MORAN**

Computer Science Leader

# **ABOUT**

I am extremely passionate about leading people into the next generation of Computer Science. I have over 10 years of experience in optimizing programming. In the past few years, my projects have focused on Artificial Intelligence and Machine Learning. I am looking forward to using my skills to help push the envelope and enhance the customer (both internal and external) experience.

## CONTACT

Milwaukee, WI

e: alexremingtonm@gmail.com

## LANGUAGES

Chinese - Intermediate

# INVOLVEMENTS —

#### **OPERATIONS COORDINATOR**

MSOE Artificial Intelligence Club | MAIC | February 2021 - Present

- Organize events on campus and virtually.
- Meet with fellow MAIC executive board members.
- Discuss how previous events have gone and what to improve for future venues.

## **CONSTROLS SUBTEAM MEMBER**

NASA Robotics Mining Competition | RMC | September 2020 - Present

- Worked on front-end development.
- Utilized Node.JS to create a modular dashboard to interact with the robot.

# **SKILLS**

In addition to fluency in the programming languages: Python, Java, JavaScript, C++;

- Web Development (5 years)
- Software Development (5 years)
- Linux (2 years)
- Machine Learning (2 years)
- Computer Vision (1 year)

# **EDUCATION**

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE: COMPUTER SCIENCE, MINOR: PHYSICS Milwaukee School of Engineering | Wisconsin | 2020 - present

#### HIGH SCHOOL DIPLOMA

Rosemount High School | Minnesota | 2020

## EXPERIENCE

## **CODING INSTRUCTOR**

Coding Minds | Remote, CA | August 2021 - Present

- Teach students practical applications of programming.
- C# and Lua programming languages.
- Unity and Roblox game engines.
- Engine specific function calls and proper debugging.

## **COMPUTER PROGRAMMING INSTRUCTOR**

Milwaukee School of Engineering | Wisconsin | October 2020 - May 2021

- Teach students the fundamentals of programming.
- Importance of sequential ordering while utilizing loops and conditional statements.
- Students are taught how to interact with a 2D environment to display the results of the program.
- Emphasizing the importance of spatial relations.

# **CUSTOMER SERVICE ASSOCIATE**

Target Corporation | Apple Valley, MN | Sept 2018 - Aug 2019

• Providing excellent customer service to guests with a wide variety of needs.

# **PROJECTS**

- TensorFlow Transfer Learning | python | Using ImageNet
- Dungeon Crawler | C++ | supporting non-Euclidian geometry
- Pac-Man Al | Java and JavaScript | using the NEAT Algorithm
- Web scraping | python | using Selenium and BeautifulSoup